

ROMAIN GIOUX

Web Developer

Always setting new goals and seeking ambitious challenges. Ready to craft interactive web environement and to solve digital puzzles.



romaingiouxdev@gmail.com

github.com/nordend4000

+33 698 117 167

in <u>linkedin.com/in/romain-gioux</u>

59 drusbergstrasse 8053 Zürich, Switzerland

Work & Residency : B Permit

LAST POSITION

Project Management Officer
Disability Support Worker

Tea Cup Cottage - Capalaba, Australia MAY 2018 - JUNE 2020

Within the Blue Tongue Adventure program, the project was to open a cafe and a shared garden to provide professional training for young adults with a disability.

- Researched a new premise.
- Scheduled and supervised works to adapt the space.
- Implemented safety regulations and risk policies.
- Logistic coordination to run activities and training for clients.

LANGUAGES

French
English
Spanish
German



TECHNICAL SKILLS

FRONT END:

JavaScript / React / Next.js HTML / CSS / SASS / SVG TailwindCss / Bootstrap SEO / Cypress / Jest Framer Motion / GSAP

BACK END: PHP/SQL

Node.js / Mongo DB / Vercel Firebase / Netlify / Heroku CROSSOVER:

VS Code / Git / NPM
Dev Tools / FTP
CompasMongoDB
MySQL workbench
WordPress / Shopify
Mac OS / Windows
Figma / Photoshop
AutoCAD / Sketchup

FEATURED PROJECTS

E-commerce Website

View Store

Source code

High quality print and digital photographies for sale.

Application built using React, Node.js, Express, MongoDB.

- Authentification for user accounts : Bcryptjs.
- Secured paiement via Stripe, Images storage via Cloudinary.
- Admin dashboard to manage orders, products and customers.

Community Network

View Website

Source code

Social App to connect outdoor sport addicts.

Application built using React, Firebase, Leaflet, Bootstrap.

- Authentification & Database : Firebase, Firestore.
- Interactive map : Leaflet & GeoCode.
- User Interface: Customised Bootstrap.
- More projects built from scratch : Visit My Portfolio

EDUCATION / TRAINING

Web Development Training: since OCTOBER 2019

OpenClassrooms, online courses, tutorials, official documentation...

En General English Certificat: FEBRUARY 2018 - APRIL 2018

Intensive English courses B2+ : Australian Pacific College, Brisbane

Humanitarian Logistic Bachelor: SEPTEMBER 2013 - JUNE 2014

Supply chain coordination training: Bioforce Institute - France
High School Certificate: JULY 2004

Civil Engineering Science : Gilbert Romme High School, France

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

Technical Draftsman

OCTOBER 2017 - JANUARY 2018

Rector Lesage Group - Ravel, France

In charge of technical reviews in the engineering office of a factory for concrete element prefabrication.

- Established work plans on AutoCad software to create modular concrete floorings and beams.
- Evaluated and diagnosed customers requests, provided estimates, elements sizing and work plans.

Quality control Technician

OCTOBER 2016 - AUGUST 2017

CEMB - VICAT Cement Group - Fillinges, France

In charge of concrete quality control for a building materials laboratory after an internal training.

- Normalized and certified tests for all kind of concretes produced in 10 concrete production units.
- Analysed the test results, monitored, reported and followed up with customers.

Technical Salesman

MAY 2016 - OCTOBER 2016

L'Entrepôt du Bricolage - Annemasse, France

In charge of customer technical advisories in building materials trade.

- Order management for replenishment, improvement of the storage process and safety requirements.
- Humanitarian Logistic Manager

SEPTEMBER 2014 - MARCH 2016

Doctors Without Borders - Geneva, Switzerland

Construction Project Manager: Boga, Democratic Republic of Congo (3 months)

Monitored and implemented rehabilitations and construction for an hospital and several health centres.

- Supervised technical works, team management and progress follow-up.
- Ensured logistical aspects: budgeting, subcontracting, supply chain, purchase and storage process.
- Vaccination Logistic Manager: Kabalo, Democratic Republic of Congo (3 months)

Managed and planned logistic activities of an emergency vaccination campaign for a measle outbreak.

- Supervised logistic team to ensure transportation of medical teams, materials and cold chain.
- Scheduled 50 000 vaccinations with 160 team members within 4 weeks in over 50 villages.
- Hospital Logistic Manager: Leogane, Haiti (6 months)

Supervised logistics team & technical activities: transport, maintenance, team facilities, water, energy.

- In charge of the storage process and streamlining of materials excess with donations before closure.
- Developed and implemented a rehabilitation project for a partner hospital close to the 2010 earthquake's epicentre: masonry, water supply modernisation, refurbishment and electricity.

Construction Supervisor

SEPTEMBER 2004 - APRIL 2013

BATICENTRE SARL - Cebazat, France

In charge of building site management for masonry, reinforced concrete and excavation operations.

- Supervised Team Leader of different building sites : management of 25 to 40 employees.
- Followed onsite activities to ensure smooth and efficient progress of projects.
- Ensured public relations in meetings to coordinate the diverse step of the constructions.
- Scheduled technical equipment requirements and planed equipment maintenance.
- Provided an efficient supply chain for materials and managed storage processes.
- Assessed work quality to ensure that the terms of reference and safety requirements are respected.
- Evaluated proposals, achieved estimates and quantified needs for new projects and public tenders.
- Established work plans to report technical aspects of the building sites.

VOLUNTEERING

OCTOBER 2013 - JUNE 2014

ARIMC Association - Lyon, France

Project with a participatory approach helping an association supporting people with disabilities.

- Design, implementation and activities management of a shared garden for people with disabilities.
- Creation and manufacturing of gardening tables adapted for people in wheelchairs.
- Established work plans and reported building instructions to extend this project for a retirement home.

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS & SOFT SKILLS

TEAM WORKS

PROGRAMMING

ADAPTABILITY

MULTI TASKING

PROBLEM SOLVING

TEAM LEADING

PROJECT MANAGEMENT

CAPACITY TO LEARN

WORK UNDER PRESSURE

PERSONAL INTERESTS

CODING

FAMILY

PARAGLIDING

TECHNOLOGIES

PHOTOGRAPHY

SKI TOURING

INTERNET

TRAVEL

SCUBA DIVING

REFEREES

Alex SHAW

Tea Cup Cottage

Executive Director

alex@tea-cupcottage.com

+61 409 896 311

Rebecca ANDERSON

Doctors Without Borders
Project Medical Referent
randelallana@gmail.com
+41 766 077 523